## **Gethin Jones**

# Junior Software Developer

gethin.jones28@gmail.com | 07415 407 776 London | <u>GitHub</u>, <u>Portfolio</u>, <u>LinkedIn</u>

#### **Personal Statement**

My journey in tech began in 2014 sat in my shed pondering how technology could be used to control prosthetic limbs. This desire to help others was combined with a huge interest in the global scope of the web and how well-built web apps could spread awareness about important topics like climate change, or assist users in their daily lives. After my first taste of JavaScript, making web apps became a much-enjoyed hobby, playing around with data visualisation and front-end development. My enthusiasm for problem-solving led me to take on full-stack Javascript development where I hope to apply my skills in a long-term position. A broad knowledge of topics related to digital experiences and their applied aesthetics continues to inspire my vision while creating solutions.

#### **Technical Skills**

**Languages:** JavaScript & TypeScript (Node.js and browser environments)

Front-End Development: HTML & CSS, React.js, React Native w/ Expo, Foundation.js, Jquery.js

**Back-End Development:** Node.js, Express, SQL, PostgreQSL (PSQL) **Testing:** Test-Driven Development (TDD) with Jest and SuperTest

Database Management: Design, query & optimization of PostgreSQL databases, MongoDB, Firestore

Hosting: Cloudflare, Netlify, Render

Other Frameworks & Libraries: Meteor.js (leveraging Node.js and MongoDB), Three.js (data

visualisation), Cordova (mobile app development)

Git for version control | Agile development | Paired programming | Web Performance Optimisation | Responsive design (Media Queries, Flex-Box, CSS Grids ) | CSS preprocessors | SEO

## **Projects**

NC Project Back End: A robust back end for a fictional news website

NC Project: Responsive Front end built using React w/ Joy UI for the fictional news website

NC Group Project: Parking app using TypeScript, React Native with Expo, Firebase, Tamagui, MapLibre

Ready To Work: Real-time web app created with Meteor, node.js, MongoDB, BLAZE & Foundation

Data Visualisation: Interactive web app showing world sustainability data on a 3D globe with D3.JS

## **Professional Development**

## Junior Software Developer | Northcoders Software Development Bootcamp | Oct 24 - Mar 25

(Intensive JavaScript Development Bootcamp covering back-end and front-end to refresh and develop my skills for a permanent career change)

- Developed scalable back-end systems with performance optimization and modular code architecture
- Built RESTful APIs using Node.js and Express, ensuring best practices in web security and efficient data flow between the client and server
- Designed and implemented server-side logic for dynamic web applications, integrating both Firestore and PostgreSQL for robust data storage and retrieval
- Leveraged middleware in Express to handle authentication, request validation, and error handling
- Built responsive user interfaces using React.js styled with modern CSS3 design
- Gained Testing and debugging skills with good knowledge of testing methodologies and tools
- Utilised Agile Development and teamwork skills in paired programming sprints

Other - The Odin Project, EPIC React, Udemy Full-Stack Web Development

## **Experience**

#### Warehouse Assistant | London Bridge Books/ Booktrolls Warehouse | 2021 - 2024

- Exposure to a complex digital stock handling system in a large book warehouse
- Proven adaptability and ability to learn quickly in different situations and tasks
- Regularly achieved bonuses for maintaining excellent accuracy and efficiency

#### Stock Management - John Lewis | 2020-2021 | 2013- 2015 (break for study + travel)

- Working for a large well-established business with exposure to various departments and stock flow
- Time Management Ability to switch tasks to meet the moving needs of the business
- Independent, driven and responsible work ethic regularly commended by management

#### Freelance Digital Designer | 2018-2020

- Professional Bespoke Website design for several small businesses and independent clients
- Strong communication skills listening to the needs of clients and explaining features
- Experience in creating solutions for a range of projects utilising APIs for custom music playback, complex CSS animations, effects and transitions, video backgrounds and media queries for responsive design

#### Web Content & Development Administrator | Perfect Document Creation | 2017-2019

- Versatility through Bulk Asset Creation, Social Media roles and Website Administration
- Precise attention to detail while in charge of data entry responsibilities for thousands of products
- Problem-solving ability and strong analytical skills to find effective solutions quickly

Previous experience available on request

#### Education

#### Brunel University | Digital Design Bsc | 2014 - 2018 | First Class Honors

Leaving a job building skateboards to pursue building web applications at age 22, I had clear goals and applied myself to the broad scope of topics covered\*. My disciplined approach to learning earned me a first-class honors degree, an exhibit at the Young Designer of the Year Exhibition and skills that were an invaluable foundation to later becoming a full-stack developer.

\*Key modules included: Web Design & Development | Server-side Development | Mobile Web Development | Programming for Digital Media | Data Modelling | Interaction Design and Usability (UI/UX) | Digital Design Theory | Digital Experiences | Business for Digital Creative Industries | Experimental Digital Futures | Marketing & Professional Development | Video Production | Design Practice | Applied Media Aesthetics | Graphics | 3D Design & Animation | Digital Photography

#### **Hobbies and Interests**

**Travelling:** Love to get immersed in culture - highlights have been trekking the Himalayas in Nepal, exploring Cercedilla in Madrid, Mountain villages in Mexico, the deserts of Hampi in India and Athens **Bouldering:** Keen climber when not working off my dad-bod since my little girl was born last year **Music:** Proud listener of almost anything and everything. Dabble in recording vocals for multiple genres (love a bit of classic boom-bap hip-hop). Amateur producer of weird music, largely drum and bass and DJ of varied vinyl or digital sets

**Hiking and Wild camping:** Spent 6 months working in Scotland and exploring hammock spots on a motorcycle

**Skateboarding:** Mostly to get around these days on my cruiser overtaking cyclists